>> Kyle Simpson: 我们要回来谈谈函数表达式练习。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We're back to talk
about the function expressions exercise.
希望你发现这个很有挑战性
Hopefully you've found this one
is efficiently challenging,
把你的大脑扭转在思考功能及其名字的问题上
twist your brain around thinking
about functions and their names and
函数所属的位置以及如何定义它们。
where functions belong and
how to define them.
尤其是在箭头功能上的差异和
And especially with the arrow functions,
the differences and
这些样式之间的可读性有很大的差别。
there can be very stark differences
in readability between those styles.
我们要开始执行打印记录功能
We're gonna start by implementing
the printRecords function.
在此再次说明，如果您愿意，将要求我们在
Again the spec here, if you will,
is asking us to take in a list of
学生标识，按学生标识获取学生记录。
student Ids,
get the student record by it's student Id.
我已经注意到了你可以发现
And I've already noticed,
you could notice that there's going to be
至少还有一个我们要做的地方就在这里
at least one other place where we need to
to do that, and that's gonna be down here.
所以我已经知道我需要这个实用程序
So I already know that's
a utility I'm gonna need,
通过其标识来访问学生记录。
accessing a student record by its ID.
所以我要先写那个功能
So I'm gonna start by
writing that function first,
我会说函数 getStudentById ，这将采用 studentId。
I'll say function getStudentById, and
that's gonna take in the studentId.
>> Kyle Simpson: 它需要从该阵列中返回我的记录。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And it needs to
return me the record from that array.
因此，它通过阵列进行搜索，找到匹配标识的匹配项。
So it's got a search through the array and
find the one that matches by the ID.
我们不需要实施自己的搜索算法
We don't need to implement
our own search algorithm
因为 JavaScript 数组与它们上的六重查找方法一样。
because JavaScript arrays as vs
six heavy find method on them.
所以我们只是简单地使用我们正在寻找的阵列
So we're just gonna simply use, and
the array that we're looking over is
称为 studentRecords ，所以我们会说 studentRecords.find()。
called studentRecords, so
we're gonna say studentRecords.find().
而 find() 函数需要回调，
And the find() function takes a callback,
对数组中的每个项调用该回调。
that callback is invoked for
each item in an array.
只要第一次回归真实或真实的价值
And whenever the first of those
returns true or a truthy value,
那么将返回数组中的值，不是 true ，而是返回数组。
then that value from the array is
returned, not the true, but the array.
差不多就像过滤器，我们基本就需要回归真实
It's almost like filter,
we basically just need to return true
只要我们找到了我们想要的东西
whenever we have found
the thing that we want.
因此，如果我们已匹配 studentId ，那么
So, if we have matched the studentId, for
示例， >> Kyle Simpson: 我仅使用
example,
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I'll just use
记录在此处。
record here.
我们知道匹配标识的方式是 (record.id == studentId ) 。
The way we know that we have matched
an ID is if the (record.id == studentId).
>> Kyle Simpson: 将在数组中找到记录并将其返回，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And that will find
the record in the array and return it,
我得先从我的打印记录中注销
I'm gonna need that very
first off in my printRecords.
我想做的第一件事就是把我的名单
So, the very first thing that
I wanna do is turn my list of
将 Ids 记录到 studentRecords 的列表中，全部正确。
record Ids into a list of studentRecords,
all right.
因为这可能不是记录标识的完整列表，所以
Because this may not be
the whole list of recordIds, so
我基本上是从我想打印的记录中找到一个子集。
I'm basically getting a subset, by ID
of the records that I wanna print out.
所以我可以做地图功能
So I can do a map function for that,
我可以带 recordIds， >> Kyle Simpson:
I can take the recordIds,
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Which is
一组数字 studentIds ，我可以将它映射到
an array of numbers studentIds,
and I can map it and
把它变成一组我可以打印出来的学生记录
turn it into an array of student
records that I can then print out.
所以我得先整理好
So, but first I'll have to sort them, so
我要打电话给 getRecord 好吗
that function I'll call getRecord, okay.
所以我要去找一个 studentId 我得去找它
So I'm taking in a studentId,
and I need to go find it and
那我就立刻意识到这个宏的功能，对吧 ?
then I immediately realize already
have this macro function, right?
这就是我刚写的
That's the one that I just wrote,
所以基本 getStudentById 是我的宏功能。
so basically getStudentById
is my macro function.
你和我一起吗
Are you with me?
相反，作为内联函数表达式，我将其作为
Instead of passing that in as an inline
function expression I have it as
一个独立功能，因为我知道我需要
a standalone function, because I have the
foreknowledge of knowing I'm gonna need
在这里第二次的时候
that a second time here in just a moment.
好吧那我们就回电话记录吧
[LAUGH] Okay, so
what we get back we could call records.
这些是我们想打印的学生记录
These are the student records
that we wanna print, but
我们不能把它们印在清单上因为我们需要按名字来排序
we can't print them just yet
because we need to sort this list by name.
所以我们得说特委
So we need to say records.sort,
sort 函数为， >> Kyle Simpson: Frustraty 是 mutator
the sort function is,
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Frustratingly a mutator
而不是返回新阵列，它会由于性能原因而发生突变。
rather than returning a new array, it
mutates in place for performance reasons.
所以我们不需要说记录等于记录那样
So we don't actually need to say
records equals records, that sort,
我们就可以叫特委了它就把它变了
we can just call records.sort and
it mutates it.
如果你在乎的话你可以得到回报但我觉得回报率很重要
You could get a return value if you cared,
but I tend to think the return value makes
看起来好像不是在发生变异的时候
it look like it's not mutating
in place when it is so,
我通常称它为一个旁观者，好的。
I usually just call it as a mutator,
all right.
所以，如果你用它在数值上对它进行 alpha 数字排序的话，
So, sort if you call it with nothing it
does an alpha numeric sort on the values,
问题是我们的价值观是物体
and the problem with that is
our values are objects and
当我们谈到这类单位时，它们会被两个物体所组成。
they are gonna string of by two objects
as we talked about the types unit.
因此，我们需要提供一个可以进行比较的函数调用。
So, we're gonna need to provide a function
call back that can do the comparison.
所以我要回电话
So I will call this function call back,
sortbyNameAscending，根据它的内容。
sortbyNameAscending, according
to what it said.
而这个函数回拨的方式是它接收到两个记录。
And the way this function call back
works is it receives two records.
所以我们将接收记录 d1和 record2
So we will receive record1,
and record2, and
我们应该做的是如果 record1 小于 record2。
what we're supposed to do is if
record1 is less than record2.
意思是录音机应该更早出现在名单上
Meaning record1 should show
up earlier in the list,
那就应该回报不到 0 比 -1的东西
then were supposed to return
something less than 0 like -1.
如果它大于记录 2 我们就应该返回 1
If it's greater than record2
we're supposed to return 1,
如果它等于我们要返回 0
and if it's equal to we're
supposed to return 0.
因此，我们可以说 ( record1.name )
So, we can say if (record1.name
< record2.name)。
&lt; record2.name).
现在我们有机会知道在这个数据结构中
Now we have the advantage of knowing
that in this data structure the names
都是字符串
are always strings.
所以最后一件事不能用 alpha 数字做
So this last thing is not gonna course
it's just gonna do in alpha numeric
比较。
comparison.
如果字符串小于此字符串，
If the string is less than this one,
从数字上说它会提前在名单上
alpha numerically then it's
gonna sort early in the list.
因此，如果 record1.name 小于 record2.name ，那么我们可以返回 -1。
So if record1.name is less than
record2.name, then we can return -1.
如果 record1.name > record2.name，
If record1.name &gt; record2.name,
我们将返回 1号
we an return 1, and
否则，我们将返回 0。
otherwise, we'll return 0.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 是吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yes?
>> 扬声器 2: 仅作为实践问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Just as a practice question.
即使假定您知道 sortByNameAsc
Even if assuming you
knew that sortByNameAsc
按姓名升序排列，您将不在任何其他位置使用。
by name ascending you would
not be using anywhere else.
你会考虑提取吗
Would you ever consider extracting that?
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yes I would.
>> 扬声器 2: 然后按顺序进行排序，按行排序。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And then just have
records.sort, sort by, okay.
>> Kyle Simpson: 尤其如此，因为按名称排序
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And it's especially
true because this sort by name
升函数不依赖于词法范围的任何内容，
ascending function doesn't rely
upon anything in the lexical scope,
它不需要被植入
it doesn't need to be embedded.
那么，我们其实是会在另一次的演习中提出这个问题的。
Well, we will actually come to
that question in another exercise.
所以我们整理了记录清单，现在我们只需要打印记录。
So we have sorted the list of records,
now we simply need to print the records.
又因为锻炼的精神是使用功能，
And again because the spirit of
the exercise is to use functions,
我们要用我们的朋友 forEach
let's use our friend, forEach.
我们可以说 records.forEach。
We can say records.forEach.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 我们将在这里做简单的 console.log 声明
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And we're just gonna
do a simple console.log statement here,
我会说记录的名字
I'll say record.name.
然后在括号里我会说记录 id 和
And then in parenthesis
I'll say record.id and
那么我们就会在这里发表一个言论如果他们得到报酬我们会说报酬的
then we'll have an expression here
that if they are paid we'll say paid.
record.id Iseorry record.id 为 true 或
So record.id I'm sorry
record.paid which is true or
假的我们会说工资还是没付
false, and we'll say paid or not paid.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 好的，有我们的打印记录功能。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay, so
there is our print record function.
现在给学生报名，期待看我
Now paid students to enroll,
the expect the read me
要求看整个学生的记录。
requirement say that it should look
throughout the student records.
正在检查哪些已支付但尚未支付
Checking to see which ones are paid but
not yet
注册，表示他们支付的是真实的，但
enrolled, meaning they
have a paid of true but
其标识尚未存在于当前注册数组中。
their ID is not already in
that current enrollment array.
所以，让我们来看看我们要得到的是一份清单
So, let's see that what
we're going to get is a list
然后我们将返回的是
of idstoEnroll, and
then what we're going to return is
包含当前注册的新阵列。
a new array that includes
the current enrollment.
所以我们会把这个注册的
So we will spread out
the currentEnrollment, and
那么我们将会包括我们在 idsToEnroll中所拥有的任何东西
then we will include whatever
we've got in idsToEnroll.
>> Kyle Simpson: 那么我们如何获取 idsToEnroll?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So
how do we get the idsToEnroll?
我们可以用 studentRecords开始
Well, we can start with
the studentRecords.
>> Kyle Simpson: 我们可以过滤 studentRecords，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And
we can filter studentRecords,
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 那只是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That was only going
把我们的人都记下来
to get us down to the studentRecords, and
那我们就得把名单映射到身份证清单里了
then we're gonna need to map
that list into a list of IDs.
但我们可以通过过滤 studentRecords开始
But we can start by filtering
the studentRecords,
所以我们会说需要登记
and so we will say, needsToEnroll.
>> Kyle Simpson: 我们想把它放在那个名单上
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And we wanna keep
it in that list if record.paid,
他们已经付出了代价
meaning they have paid and
他们还没有目前的报名情况。
they are not already
in current enrollment.
还有一个内置的 JavaScript 数组方法
And there is a built in
JavaScript array method called
在 2016 年的 ES 中也添加了这个时间。
includes also added this time in ES 2016.
数组包含在数组中搜索值并使我们为 true 或
Array includes searches for
a value in the array and gives us true or
如果它在那里就会是假的
false if it's there.
所以我们不需要我去做那个我们以前所做的小把戏的索引。
So we don't need me to do that down
little index of trick that we used to do.
因此，我可以简单地说，如果当前的注册不包含当前注册，请将其包含在记录中。
So I can simply say if current enrollments
if not current enrollments includ.record,
这让我有了记录但我不需要记录
that gives me a record,
but I don't need a record.
我真正需要的是身份证所以现在我要
What I actually need is the ID,
so now I need to do
从记录中获取 StudentId 的映射。
a map which gets the StudentId
from the record.
>> Kyle Simpson: 现在填充 idsToEnroll。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And
now that populates idsToEnroll.
所以我们没有修改过 currentenrollment，
So we have not modified
the currentenrollment,
我们只是在重新排列新阵列让你做点什么
we're simply returning the new array for
you to do something with it.
最后我们有了再无报酬的
Finally we have the remindUnpaid,
这个要求又说我们应该把一个 studentIds 列在一个名单上。
again the requirements say that we
should take a list of studentIds.
仅将该列表过滤为那些记录处于未支付状态的人员，
Filter that list to only those
whose records are in unpaid status,
然后将过滤后的列表传给 printRecords。
and then pass that filtered
list to printRecords.
所以我们要做另一个过滤器
So we're gonna do another filter,
这次我们要做记录过滤器
this time we're gonna do recordIds.filter,
and
我们要做的就是那些不派的人
what we're gonna get back
from that is the unpaidIds.
>> Kyle Simpson: 现在我们有学生标识，但我们需要记录。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Now we have
the student id but we need the record.
所以我们要记录下的记录
So we need to get the record
by saying record = and
然后使用我先前写的小助手 getStudentById。
then we use that little helper that
I wrote earlier, getStudentById.
>> Kyle Simpson: 然后我们需要说，如果记录不记录，那么支付。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And then we need to say,
if record.paid if not record.paid.
>> Kyle Simpson: 因此，将向我提供尚未支付的记录的标识列表。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So that will give me the
list of ids who's record is in the unpaid
状态，那么我应该简单地将该列表传递到 printRecords中。
status, then I should simply pass
that list into printRecords.